<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Blog Name</title>
  <subtitle>Blog subtitle</subtitle>
  <id>http://blog.url.com/blog</id>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/blog"/>
  <link href="http://blog.url.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2016-03-14T17:00:00-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Constellation Approach to Business Technology</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/constellation-approach-business-technology"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/constellation-approach-business-technology</id>
    <published>2016-03-14T17:00:00-07:00</published>
    <updated>2016-03-16T11:45:13-07:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Self-driving cars promise to re-imagine the relationship between cities, people and transportation while Uber takes fat chunks out of the taxi industry. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Newspapers struggle with relevance—the value of ad space having plummeted as the expense of publishing dropped to near zero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Investors stand strong behind a company like Amazon while years of losses stretch into decades out of hope that it will one day turn its status as the default place where people go to buy online into an avalanche of profits that bury past losses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technology is changing the business landscape quickly. But it isn’t just threatening old business models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New technology also brings new automation opportunities letting you and your colleagues get more done in less time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Constellation Approach to Business Technology helps you understand business applications, how they relate to each other, and choose the best combination of technologies to balance growth, flexibility, and costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;How Business Applications Have Changed in the Last 15+ Years&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until around the start of the new millennium, data stayed primarily within the business application. You’ve been able to integrate enterprise and legacy apps, but integration was time-consuming and expensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As cloud computing grew in popularity and developing business software became cheaper, stand-alone applications focusing on solving increasingly niche problems flourished. Application programming interfaces (APIs) that let developers integrate apps became more common and then expected. APIs also started to become more consistent and easier to use alongside this explosion of options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The leading cloud applications in each category started using their APIs to build native integrations with each other. These integrations are at the point now where native integrations between the leading products in different software categories compete with and even exceed fully integrated suites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upstart and niche cloud products emerged to solve increasingly specific problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typically these smaller products would be less expensive than the leading cloud options, and needed to integrate with the leaders in other applications categories in order to compete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon a variety of middleware applications would spring up giving you more integration options than native and custom integrations created by the respective product teams and their customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of these middleware applications provided deep, powerful integrations between few products, like exporting Salesforce data to Excel and back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Others gave lots of shallow integrations between lots of different applications letting you trigger actions in one app from another or copying one field from one system to another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table class="text-center table-text-top"&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;th style="background-color:#ff8f4d; width:33%;"&gt;
            &lt;strong&gt;Enterprise Suite&lt;/strong&gt;
        &lt;/th&gt;
        &lt;th style="background-color:#86e400; width:33%;"&gt;
            &lt;strong&gt;Cloud Niche/Upstart&lt;/strong&gt;
        &lt;/th&gt;
        &lt;th style="background-color:#ff8f4d; width:33%;"&gt;
            &lt;strong&gt;Cloud Leader&lt;/strong&gt;
        &lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td style="background-color:#ff8f4d; width:33%;"&gt;service partners build custom integrations&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td style="background-color:#86e400; width:33%;"&gt;develop own integrations&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td style="background-color:#ff8f4d; width:33%;"&gt;attract powerful integrations&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td style="background-color:#ff8f4d; width:33%;"&gt;costly to integrate&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td style="background-color:#86e400; width:33%;"&gt;moderately costly to integrate&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td style="background-color:#ff8f4d; width:33%;"&gt;low cost to integrate&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
        &lt;td style="background-color:#ff8f4d; width:33%;"&gt;costly to license&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td style="background-color:#86e400; width:33%;"&gt;inexpensive to license&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;td style="background-color:#ff8f4d; width:33%;"&gt;moderately costly to license&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td colspan="3" style="border: 1px solid #B6B6B6;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shallow Integration Middleware&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
shallow integration between many applications&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td colspan="3" style="border: 1px solid #B6B6B6;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deep Integration Middleware&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
deep integration between a small number of applications&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This explosion of stand-alone, SaaS business applications, with multiple layers of integration options, gives you more varied options towards solving a wider variety of challenges and unprecedented flexibility to manage the flow of information through your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where before you had to get an expensive piece of software that would require extensive configuration and customization before you could start using it effectively, now you can probably find a solution that will work for you almost immediately and at a lower cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Hidden Cost of Cheap&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Individual products and integrations are straightforward. The full web of products and integrations is incredibly complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The overall cost of one or two low-cost, poorly integrated applications is negligible. Particularly if the applications solve an important business problem. Licensing and maintenance costs are practically non-existent in this situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The costs of poorly integrated applications grow exponentially as their number increase. Licensing is still inexpensive, but niche products attract fewer integrations. And having substandard integration options imposes a substantial tax on productivity across the company. That tax increases with each application you add.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The productivity tax is paid in the following ways:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;time spent on duplicate data entry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;poor decisions caused by poor data due to

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;data entry errors, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;missing data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lost opportunity because highly specialized tools only integrate with the strongest platforms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;increased effort to perform what are basic tasks on stronger platforms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the cost each little example of duplicate data entry or handicapped decision making is negligible, they add up and quickly dwarf the licensing costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Low-cost, niche products have their place in small businesses and solving niche problems in large ones. But their hidden costs are crippling the larger the business and more complex the technology stack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Platforms and Solutions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re not buying technology to solve a problem, then you are doing it wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When looking at an application, more features does not make a product better. In most cases, when you see a CRM that also does marketing automation, or a marketing automation suite that also has a content management system, or whatever other app that does something and something else, then the something else is almost always a very light version of an equivalent stand-alone app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It pays to be clear on what you are trying to accomplish with the software. Features are meaningless next to a great solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When looking at business applications be aware of whether you need them to be a platform (and solution) or just a solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Platforms are the core applications that you build off. They need to accommodate a variety of solutions as the company grows and they need to integrate readily with your other platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Niche products are often great solutions but lousy platforms because of the limited number of native integration options of a niche product. Your solutions need to integrate with one of your platforms, but any data that needs to go from solution to a non-integrated platform can usually get passed through via the one integrated platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t need extensive integration on a solution. Just one solid integration with a platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Solutions are also great candidates for taking risky bets on new technologies because they sit at the edge of your network of applications and cause minimal disruption to your business. The cost of switching from one experimental solution to another is low if you have a good platform. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This lets you outsource the risks of staying ahead of technology trends in your industry to venture capital firms while still reaping the benefits of cutting edge software technology investments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you start building on a platform, however, it is very difficult to switch. Each solution that you integrate with a platform is another requirement that will complicate purchasing, migrating and training if you ever grow out of the platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Expose Your Data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most agile platforms for your business data, whether they be CRM, support, accounting software or even ERP, are the ones that best expose your data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New technologies like big data and machine learning are creating new opportunities every day. Marketing and finance are getting most of the love from new technologies right now with applications that do things like identify the best prospects or the biggest financial risks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon retailers will be able to do things like plug their point of sale and inventory data into a cloud app that will pull in weather data and forecast umbrella demand while adjusting the retail price to maximize revenue in real time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Niche Big Data solutions like weather-based inventory forecasts are multiplying quickly. Businesses don’t need a data scientist to benefit from the Big Data revolution—they just need to keep their data in platforms that attract lots of integrations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Constellation Approach to Business Technology&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Constellation Approach to Business Technology is meant as a way of understanding how your business applications relate to each other and what you need them to do so that you maximize flexibility, and minimize expenses without restricting growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to apply this approach to your business, you need to do the following.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify platform categories (CRM, marketing automation, accounting) based on how you want to grow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify niche solutions that will contribute to your growth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Research integration options.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose the combination of platforms, solutions and integrations that best balance cost, simplicity, flexibility, and future growth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything in the Constellation Approach flows from understand which applications need to be platforms and then grows from there. The right platform both grows with you and gives you the best chance to take advantage of yet unimagined technologies just beyond the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Innovation presents the greatest risks and rewards. A good platform will let you take advantage of innovative solutions while reducing the costs of switching or abandoning a solution.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Twitter List Automation</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/twitter-list-automation"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/twitter-list-automation</id>
    <published>2016-02-14T16:00:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2016-02-29T14:09:38-08:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Twitter lists are a feature that nearly every digital marketer has experimented with but few use for anything other than keeping track of a select group of influencers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lists seem like they would be quite useful to sales reps and account managers trying to build relationships with prospects and accounts. In practice, this isn’t true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The percentage of people actively using Twitter is quite low. I would guess that perhaps 90 percent of prospects or accounts for most businesses won’t be using Twitter actively which makes for a lot of wasted time maintaining targeted lists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However with a little automation, Twitter lists can be a practical, everyday tool for sales reps and account managers. The automation handles the basic maintenance letting your people focus on building relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Create the Twitter Lists&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing you’re going to need to do is create empty Twitter lists to hold customer and prospect info. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to create separate lists for each sales person or account manager, then you will have to create a separate list for each (ie. Damon’s Prospects as opposed to just Prospects).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create the lists, log in to Twitter and open the Profile and Settings menu hidden under your Twitter icon at the top right of the web interface and select Lists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then create as many lists as necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Prepare Your CRM&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to simplify later configuration and reduce the amount of redundant work that Zapier will do, we’re going to want to store the Twitter handle in CRM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t already have one, create a Twitter Handle field in your CRM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Set Up the Zapier Integration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re going to use Zapier to pull prospect and customer info from CRM, enhance that information with social media account information from FullContact which we will return to CRM before adding any Twitter accounts found by FullContact to the appropriate list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create a new Zap that triggers whenever you add a &lt;strong&gt;New Contact&lt;/strong&gt; to your CRM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="New Contact CRM Trigger in Zapier" src="../assets/images/2016/crm-new-contact-trigger-4817f933.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, create a Filter that checks that the CRM email field exists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Email Exists Filter in Zapier" src="../assets/images/2016/email-exists-filter-f5a7df50.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Select FullContact for your action, connecting your FullContact account to Zapier if necessary, and choose &lt;strong&gt;Find a Person&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="FullContact Find a Person Zapier Search" src="../assets/images/2016/fullcontact-find-person-9c62a76a.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;strong&gt;Save + Continue&lt;/strong&gt;, test the step and then connect your CRM email and phone number, if you like, to FullContact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="FullContact Find a Person Zapier Search Settings" src="../assets/images/2016/fullcontact-find-person-settings-c3fa07c7.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Test the step again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that the test will tell you whether the step was a success or not. If you get a success message but check the data returned it will be for the wrong record. That is okay. It is just a quirk of the FullContact-Zapier integration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is all that we need for this Zap. However, there are a lot of potentially useful additions to this Zap that are detailed in the optional selection at the end of this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Automate Twitter List Creation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of CRM systems are limited to triggering Zapier when a contact is created and not when it is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that, for many CRM systems, we can’t just check if FullContact found a Twitter handle, send the handle to CRM and trigger a new series of Zaps to add contacts with Twitter handles to the appropriate list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cover this topic in more depth in my post titled &lt;em&gt;Creative On Update Zapier Triggers&lt;/em&gt;, but basically what you will need to do is set your CRM up to create a new tag or a new note when the &lt;em&gt;Twitter Handle&lt;/em&gt; field we created in the CRM gets filled out and then watch for that tag to trigger the list creation Zaps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The specifics vary by CRM. This is what I did for Agile CRM and then set up a trigger to run this daily since I don’t have an update trigger in CRM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Add Tag Automation in Agile CRM" src="../assets/images/2016/crm-add-tag-automation-bc35d018.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving back to Zapier, we’re going to watch for this tag, or note or whatever you needed to create to trigger the Zap, and then filter contacts by Owner to get prospects in the right list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The specifics of the trigger will depend on whether you can trigger on update or have to use a workaround and, if you used a workaround, on what workaround you used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, I triggered the Zap from Agile CRM using the &lt;strong&gt;New Tag to Contact&lt;/strong&gt; trigger with a &lt;strong&gt;Tag Name&lt;/strong&gt; of &lt;em&gt;Twitter&lt;/em&gt; matching the tag I’m automatically creating in CRM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have your trigger set up, add a &lt;em&gt;(Text) Exactly matches&lt;/em&gt; Filter on the owner email field from CRM using the email address of the sales or account rep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may also want to filter by the status or funnel stage, however, if everyone is using CRM properly and is setting the owner of the contact, then you probably won’t need a status or funnel stage filter as we’ll be matching against the owner’s email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, create a Twitter &lt;em&gt;Add User to List&lt;/em&gt; action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Add User to Twitter List in Zapier" src="../assets/images/2016/add-user-twitter-list-f0f91431.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Save and connect your Twitter account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Select the Twitter list that you created and map the Twitter handle from your CRM to Zapier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Add User to Twitter List in Zapier Settings" src="../assets/images/2016/add-user-twitter-list-settings-9c2187ee.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you need to repeat this last series of steps for each sales or account rep for whom you’re creating Twitter lists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Drawbacks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The one possible drawback of this automation is that there isn’t an easy way to remove people from lists. Zapier simply doesn’t have a Remove from List option even though Twitter’s API supports it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some salespeople are happy to maintain a relationship after the sale and are fine with their list of prospects including former prospects that they’ve already either won or lost. But others would like that sort of thing cleaned up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is less of an issue for account managers because accounts don’t normally churn as fast as sales prospects qualify or disqualify, but it is still a problem with no easy automated solution.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Extract Email Domain with Zapier</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/extract-email-domain-zapier"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/extract-email-domain-zapier</id>
    <published>2016-01-31T16:00:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2016-02-22T14:04:34-08:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When you capture information online there is always a balance between asking for more information and making it as easy as possible for your visitors to complete their task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You want more information to help you decide what to do with the person but you also want to maximize the number of people who give you their contact information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a B2B context, email addresses are king. Every form has an email field. But everything else is up for debate particularly when you need more information to qualify whether it is worth having a sales rep contact the lead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a lot that you can do with just the email address particularly if you get the email domain from the address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Internal Notifications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Extracting the email domain from your contacts lets you trigger a number of useful internal notifications when working complex sales with long sales cycles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re selling high-priced (and hopefully high-value) items to other businesses, then often there will be several people included in the decision to buy. These sales usually take a long time. I’ve seen sales reps working an account for years before finally closing a sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notifying sales reps when a new contact from one of their accounts starts interacting with your marketing materials can be of great value. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can mean that a good prospect that wasn’t ready several years ago is now in the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or, if they are already in a sales cycle, it can tell the sales rep who are some of the other decision makers who will be involved in the purchase. They can then do more research seeing what sorts of content they read on the site and learn more about the individual online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can trigger these notifications by matching email domains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Lead Scoring&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way that you can use email domain is in scoring leads that your sales team hasn’t spoken to before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, presuming you’re working a complex sale with long sales cycles, seeing multiple contacts from the same email domain is a good signal that the company associated with that domain is in the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matching multiple email domains over the space of a few months should give leads a big boost to their lead score and trigger a follow up from the sales team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Collecting Pre-Sales Data&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The email domain is also useful for collecting pre-sales data from other databases like Salesforce’s data.com, Dun and Bradstreet or LinkedIn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the company name is unreliable when you’re tying to match different data sources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can have separate legal names, trade names and DBAs (doing business as).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes people include the designations like Ltd. and  LLC at the end of the name, but other people often leave them out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You even have problems with adding or leaving off the period in Ltd. or using abbreviations versus spelling out &lt;em&gt;Limited&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can have the same company name used by different companies in different parts of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes people even make typos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally, you can have conglomerates of multiple companies each with their own name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve got a verified email address, then you have a unique identifier for the individual and for the company that owns that domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can use the domain to more reliably get data about the company than you can a company name typed in to an online form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One problem with using the domain is that you can have multiple domains for a company. Or different domains for different departments or regions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The LinkedIn API helps with this challenge. It associates multiple domains with each company. You can use the API to look up company data by domain and find other domains associated with the company and then match against all of the domains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Salesforce only lets you look up by website and email domains are often different from website domains and you won’t capture the full range of email domains associated with a particular company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you connect with a data source, you can pull all sorts of information like the name, number of employees, revenue (if they are public) and all sorts of location data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of data source, using the email domain to look up additional information from third party databases is an advanced use and should only be done by an experienced developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Marketing Automation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of these uses for email domain assume that you have a complex sale and that you are using marketing automation and CRM. Some of the set up is best done in your marketing automation system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Filtering out Gmail, Yahoo and Live/Hotmail addresses is best done in your marketing automation system. Keeping a running list of email domains that you want to filter in the marketing automation system is easier than modifying the custom script that we’re going to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, triggering notifications and lead scoring is best done in the marketing automation system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because the specifics of each system vary a great deal, we won’t cover how exactly to set up the filtering, notifying, matching and scoring. These are the types of things that marketing automation systems do well so they shouldn’t be too difficult to set up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Zapier&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Extracting the email domain from an email address is usually a customization in marketing automation systems that is not so easy to set up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Dynamics CRM would require some scripting in Visual Basic that would only be useful for Dynamics users. Hubspot would require that you do an API integration and host your own code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re going cover how to use Zapier to extract the email domain. This way, Zapier hosts your code and you can use these instructions with any Zapier-compatible system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zapier recently launched multi-step Zaps that make this workflow possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create a new multi-step Zap that triggers when a New Contact is added to your marketing automation system (or CRM).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing you need to do is create a field to keep the email domain in your system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specifics of how to do this depend on your system, but it shouldn’t be difficult. Name the field &lt;em&gt;Email Domain&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Zapier, create a new Zap and select &lt;strong&gt;New Contact&lt;/strong&gt; as the trigger from your marketing automation/CRM system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="New Contact Zapier Trigger" src="../assets/images/new-contact-trigger-7d0fb622.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Test the step and check the contact information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next add a &lt;strong&gt;Filter&lt;/strong&gt; that checks whether the new contact has an email address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Contact Exists Zapier Filter" src="../assets/images/contact-exists-filter-08bfffb0.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now comes a little bit of code, but I promise that it will be quite painless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add a &lt;strong&gt;Code by Zapier&lt;/strong&gt; action and select &lt;strong&gt;Run Python&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;strong&gt;Input&lt;/strong&gt; section of the &lt;strong&gt;Edit Template&lt;/strong&gt; step, select the marketing automaion/CRM email field and name it &lt;em&gt;email&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be sure to keep the name lower case or else it will break the code in the next step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Extract Email Domain Settings and Code" src="../assets/images/extract-email-domain-fa997eb4.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter the following code into the &lt;strong&gt;Code&lt;/strong&gt; section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight python"&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="kn"&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nn"&gt;re&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;email&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;input&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;'email'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="n"&gt;emailatDomain&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;re&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;search&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;".+@([&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;\&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;w.]+)"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;email&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="s"&gt;'emailDomain'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;emailatDomain&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;group&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;emailatDomain&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;else&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;'Error'&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those of you with little knowledge of Python, here’s what’s going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Line 1: Import the regular expression module that will let us match patterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Line 2: Grab the input that we named email (and assigned to the email field from the marketing automation system) and make it a variable called &lt;em&gt;email&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Line 3: Search for any combination of characters or symbols until you find an @ sign, then look for one or more upper or lower case letters, numbers and periods and create a group from whatever matches this last part of the pattern. Call the whole collection emailatDomain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Line 4: Return the following for Zapier to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Line 5: Create emailDomain from the group of letters, numbers and periods after the @ sign if emailatDomain is set. Otherwise return the word &lt;em&gt;Error&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Test the code against a recent contact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we need to send the email domain back to your marketing automation or CRM system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create a new Update Contact type of Action for your marketing automation or CRM system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Update Contact Zapier Action" src="../assets/images/update-contact-490f7d3a.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Match the email address of the contact against the email field from your system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Match Contact Email" src="../assets/images/match-contact-email-113dece6.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then finally, scroll down to the &lt;strong&gt;Email Domain&lt;/strong&gt; field that you created in your system and match the &lt;strong&gt;EmailDomain&lt;/strong&gt; variable that you returned in your &lt;strong&gt;Code by Zapier&lt;/strong&gt; script.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Send Zapier Code to System" src="../assets/images/send-zapier-code-to-system-09fe5c56.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you should start getting email domains separated out from the email addresses for any new contacts that enter the system from now on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can start using the field in your chosen system to trigger notifications, score leads, or fetch additional information about the company.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Automating Feedback and Reviews</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/automating-feedback-reviews"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/automating-feedback-reviews</id>
    <published>2016-01-14T16:00:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2016-02-23T11:21:51-08:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Any business that develops a long relationship with their customers can and should automate feedback and review requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good candidates include virtually any service business:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IT outsourcing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;marketing agencies :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;construction contractors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hotels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cleaning services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;software as a service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, any business where you know the customer well enough to get their email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why would you want to automate feedback and reviews?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You want feedback because you want to improve your business.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You want online reviews because they strongly influence new business.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Automating feedback makes it consistent—automation doesn’t forget or get too busy. And by virtue of being consistent, the feedback becomes more useful as a key perfomance indicator letting you ask questions of the data. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are we doing better now than a year ago?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which departments are doing best?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which ones need help?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we’re going to do is set up something called a Net Promoter Score (NPS) survey to start with. You can learn more about NPS surveys here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chaining your review process to your feedback process lets you filter your review requests before you make them. This lets you ask happy customers for reviews while dealing with unhappy ones through other channels (or at least learn from past mistakes to do better next time).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want happy customers to share their experiences with the world. And emailing them a little nudge will help them cut out the many other distractions and get the review done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The entire process in order of execution is as follows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Send feedback request from CRM and encode the recipient’s email address in the email so they can be identified later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collect feedback in Typeform form. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Send internal notifications from Typeform for unhappy customers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trigger Zapier integration for happy customers to automatically send a follow-up review request from MailChimp.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trigger Zapier integration to return Typeform feedback to CRM for reporting purposes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can’t set things up in this order because we need to know where to point the email in step one and we need to create fields in Typeform, MailChimp and CRM before we can connect them with Zapier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Create Feedback Form - Typeform&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re going to use a service called &lt;a href="http://www.typeform.com/"&gt;Typeform&lt;/a&gt; in our examples because it creates beautiful forms, calculates your net promoter score for you, integrates widely so it can fit into our app constellation, and you can do a bunch of other cool stuff with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are already using a landing page tool like Unbounce or marketing automation platform like Hubspot or Marketo, feel free to create your feedback forms there. Or use Typeform anyway because it is awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hit the &lt;strong&gt;Create a Typeform&lt;/strong&gt; and be sure to &lt;strong&gt;Save Your Account&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="New Typeform" src="../assets/images/2016/new-typeform-506c991d.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, with your account saved, select the &lt;strong&gt;Use a template option&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Getting Started with Typeform" src="../assets/images/2016/typeform-getting-started-bee6548c.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scroll down the templates gallery and select &lt;strong&gt;Net Promoter Score&lt;/strong&gt; and then &lt;strong&gt;Use this template&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Typeform Templates" src="../assets/images/2016/typeform-templates-90787831.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typeform’s default net promoter score survey adds a bunch of demographic questions to the standard NPS survey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this information is undoubtedly useful to have, the beauty of NPS is simplicity. The main value comes from the first question which asks how likely the customer is to recommend you to a friend can be completed in ten seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second question asks, what was the reason for giving you a score. The extra effort required here makes the answers you get more valuable because whatever they write in this question is important enough that they care to take the time to tell you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider the demographics questions optional. I feel segmenting the data by things like the service given to be more valuable than demographics. Keep or delete the demographics questions as you feel appropriate&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve decided what fields that you’re going to need, you will want to add a hidden email field to the form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Select &lt;strong&gt;Hidden fields on&lt;/strong&gt;, this will require an upgrade to Pro but you can start a free trial and follow along if you prefer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Typeform NPS Questions" src="../assets/images/2016/typeform-nps-questions-72742d2b.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;strong&gt;Hidden fields&lt;/strong&gt; dialog, type &lt;em&gt;email&lt;/em&gt; and hit &lt;strong&gt;save&lt;/strong&gt;. This will let us pass the email address from your CRM/project management system/booking management system to Typeform and tie responses back to the individual who filled out the survey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Typeform Hidden Fields Dialog" src="../assets/images/2016/typeform-hidden-fields-d9d47ff0.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make whichever design changes you like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Set Up Internal Notifications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the design set up, you can now set up an internal notification. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under &lt;strong&gt;Typeform&lt;/strong&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;Configure&lt;/strong&gt;, select &lt;strong&gt;Self notifications&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;&lt;img alt="Typeform Notifications" src="../assets/images/2016/typeform-notifications-4066b67b.png" /&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under &lt;strong&gt;Send a notification to:&lt;/strong&gt; enter the recipient(s) for the notifications. The email that you used to sign up will be there by default.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;strong&gt;Reply to:&lt;/strong&gt; select the hidden email field that you added. This will let you reply to notifications and easily follow up with anyone who needs extra attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can leave everything else blank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that the Pro Trial lets you set all of this up, but it won’t work until you have a paid Pro account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Detour: Test the Form&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s always a good idea to test any automation you set up on yourself first, but with Typeform it is necessary that you have some data entered or else the integrations later won’t see the data fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go to the &lt;strong&gt;Distribute&lt;/strong&gt; section of your new form and copy the URL for your form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="New Typeform URL" src="../assets/images/2016/typeform-url-0d156bb6.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paste the URL in your browser and add your email address in place of the &lt;em&gt;xxxx&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, this URL&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://caretjuice.typeform.com/to/CxtGtd?email=xxxx"&gt;https://caretjuice.typeform.com/to/CxtGtd?email=xxxx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;becomes this URL&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://caretjuice.typeform.com/to/CxtGtd?email=damon@caretjuice.com"&gt;https://caretjuice.typeform.com/to/CxtGtd?email=damon@caretjuice.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Load the page and fill out the form. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trial accounts can test the form—just not use it with real customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Set Up Online Review Request&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typeform lets you add a few popular Zapier integrations during the Configure step. But we’re going to switch to using Zapier because it gives us more options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create or log in to your Zapier account and select &lt;strong&gt;Make a Zap&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose &lt;strong&gt;Typeform&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;New Entry&lt;/strong&gt; as your trigger and &lt;strong&gt;MailChimp&lt;/strong&gt; (or whichever tool you use for email) and &lt;strong&gt;New Subscriber&lt;/strong&gt; as your action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scroll down and connect your Typeform account to Zapier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main step here is to find your Typeform API key and copy and paste it into Zapier. Once you know how to copy and paste an API key, you’ll be an integration pro (I told you that you won’t need to learn programming).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Switch to Typeform (it’s probably best to have each application open in a different tab or window).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To find your Typeform API key, select &lt;strong&gt;My Account&lt;/strong&gt; from the drop down and scroll down to the &lt;strong&gt;Your API Key&lt;/strong&gt; section. Copy and paste that long string of nonsense in to Zapier and hit &lt;strong&gt;Continue&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Typeform API Key" src="../assets/images/2016/typeform-api-key-d1628602.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now log in to MailChimp, or whatever email program that you use, select &lt;strong&gt;Lists&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Create List&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Name this list &lt;em&gt;Promoters&lt;/em&gt;. In net promoter score surveys, people who give you a score of nine or ten are called promoters while sevens and eights are Neutrals and zero to sixes are Detractors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what I entered so you can get an idea of what to write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="MailChimp Promoters List" src="../assets/images/2016/mailchimp-promoters-list-4e86b098.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, go back to Zapier and connect your Zapier account to MailChimp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will get a popup asking you to sign in to your MailChimp account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Connect MailChimp with Zapier" src="../assets/images/2016/connect-mailchimp-zapier-d3d33b62.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Log in&lt;/strong&gt; and then select &lt;strong&gt;Continue&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Select the Typeform form that you used for the Net Promoter Score survey and &lt;strong&gt;Add a custom filter&lt;/strong&gt; using the &lt;strong&gt;How Likely Are You to Recommend Us to a Friend&lt;/strong&gt; as the field and &lt;strong&gt;Number Greater Than&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;em&gt;9&lt;/em&gt; as the filter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your results should look something like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Zapier NPS Promoters Filter" src="../assets/images/2016/zapier-nps-promoters-filter-65b02144.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are comfortable with this, click &lt;strong&gt;Continue&lt;/strong&gt; to set up the MailChimp end of the integration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your list will be &lt;strong&gt;Promoters&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Email will be the Typeform &lt;em&gt;Email&lt;/em&gt; field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And everything else can be left as is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Match MailChimp Email with Typeform Email" src="../assets/images/2016/match-mailchimp-typeform-email-41ac3b05.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scroll down and hit &lt;strong&gt;Continue&lt;/strong&gt; and then proceed to Test the Zap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the test is done, name the Zap &lt;strong&gt;NPS Promoters&lt;/strong&gt; and turn it on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Send Review Request&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we’re going to move back to MailChimp and ask for the review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need to be signed up to a paid MailChimp account to complete this step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are only using MailChimp for one-to-one automation like this, then their pay-as-you-go options are probably most economical. If you are also using MailChimp for newsletters to a big list of subscribers, then the monthly options may be more suitable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s get to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While logged in to MailChimp, select &lt;strong&gt;Automation&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Create Automation Workflow&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Create Automation Workflow in MailChimp" src="../assets/images/2016/mailchimp-create-automation-workflow-fafbe257.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;strong&gt;Choose a list to get started&lt;/strong&gt; dropdown, select &lt;em&gt;Promoters&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then under &lt;strong&gt;Select a workflow&lt;/strong&gt;, choose either &lt;em&gt;Welcome Message&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Welcome Series&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome Message is for just a single email which is all you need if you’re just asking for a review. If you want to follow up with another message asking them to sign up for your newsletter or follow you on social media, then choose Welcome Series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Select Workflow for MailChimp Automation" src="../assets/images/2016/mailchimp-select-workflow-90006382.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the next screen, give your workflow a name and set up the sender.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see what I used in the screenshot. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="MailChimp Workflow Configuration" src="../assets/images/2016/mailchimp-workflow-configuration-c4fadbe8.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, all of the default settings are fine. I added Google Analytics link tracking, but it’s not really needed since we are sending the visitors to other sites to review us. However, if you are doing a Welcome Series and will link back to your site, then you probably want to enable this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;strong&gt;Save And Exit&lt;/strong&gt; at the top-right corner and select &lt;strong&gt;Automation&lt;/strong&gt; to move to the next step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your automation is configured, but now you need to add an email message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the MailChimp Automation list under NPS Promoters click on the &lt;strong&gt;0 emails&lt;/strong&gt; link and select &lt;strong&gt;Add Email&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="MailChimp Automation Add Email" src="../assets/images/2016/mailchimp-automation-email-781de9f9.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Email Contents&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re not going to go over every step of creating the email here, but there are a few things that you should know before going ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Obey the Law&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The big one is that if you offer any payment or incentive, then the reviews will be considered paid reviews in many jurisdictions and that can put the request under truth in advertising laws. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s best avoided, so don’t offer anything for a review without getting legal advice (which this is not).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Where to Get Reviewed&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next important detail is choosing which sites that you want them to review you on and there are two things to consider here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, which sites are important. The way to do this is search Google and Bing using a query that you rank for or would like to rank for and see which review sites are already ranking. If a review site ranks well, then it is probably worth getting reviews on that site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you ran a hotel in downtown Halifax, then something like &lt;em&gt;Downtown Halifax Hotels&lt;/em&gt; makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time of writing, Google is showing sites with Google Maps reviews, Trip Advisor and Expedia so those are probably good candidates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Google Search Results for Hotel in Halifax" src="../assets/images/2016/hotel-search-results-337f5fd3.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other thing to consider is whether asking for reviews is against each sites terms of service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some sites encourage you to ask your customers to review you while it can cause problems on other sites. Read &lt;em&gt;Asking for Reviews: Is it Against the Site’s TOS&lt;/em&gt; to learn which sites encourage you to ask for reviews, which sites discourage you and what you can do instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the contents of the email, the main thing is to not get carried away and give them too many options. Listing out eight potential review sites maximizes the chances that the recipient will be a member of one site, but long lists are intimidating and giving too many choices typically reduces response rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wouldn’t give more than two options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Asking for a Google review just got a bit more tricky. If you want to include Google, and there’s a good chance that you do, then check out this post on &lt;a href="/blog/asking-google-reviews"&gt;Asking for Google Reviews&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the last thing to consider is your email design. In particular, should you do a fancy HTML email or just go with plain text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For one-to-one emails like this, I tend to prefer plain text. It’s easier and it feels like it should be more personalized even though it is automated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highly designed emails immediately put recipients on guard. I have another post on &lt;a href="/blog/html-plain-text-email"&gt;HTML vs plain text emails&lt;/a&gt; that goes deeper in to the subject if you need more convincing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as the contents of the email go, it’s best to keep it simple and to the point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subject: Thanks for Your Feedback&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just wanted to thank you for your feedback and invite you to share your experience working with us with others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d really appreciate us if you left a review on Trip Advisor, Google Maps (you’ll need to click on the review button on the right), or any other place that you feel appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks in advance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regards,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Starting the Automation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way to start the automation is in your CRM, project management system, or booking system presuming that they support some kind of triggered email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The specifics of the trigger are unique to each product so we won’t go in deep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any system that can send email and where you marking projects as complete will work. You could trigger off of a change in customer or account status. You could even use Zapier with your accounting system to send when a final invoice gets paid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the email I use. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi {{first_name}},&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we&amp;rsquo;ve finished some work for you, I wanted to ask you to give us a couple of minutes of feedback so that we can continue to get better at helping you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d appreciate it if you filled out our two question survey. The first question will take all of 15 seconds and the second is optional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit this page to complete the survey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{{owner.name}}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The personalization tags (everything inside the curly braces) will change depending on where you are sending from.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other important thing is to make sure you get the links right. In particular, make sure you include the email in the personalization tags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my Typeform-based NPS survey, the links look like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://caretjuice.typeform.com/to/CxtGtd?email=%7B%7Bemail"&gt;https://caretjuice.typeform.com/to/CxtGtd?email={{email}}&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That last &lt;em&gt;?email={{email}}&lt;/em&gt; is important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first part, &lt;em&gt;?email=&lt;/em&gt;, is telling Typeform that we are passing the email variable that we told it to watch for when we were setting up the form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second part, &lt;em&gt;{{email}}&lt;/em&gt;, is another personalization tag from my CRM telling the CRM to insert the email into this particular template. The exact format of the personalization tags varies by CRM, but curly braces are common.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without the these two elements, the whole automation sequence breaks. This is one more reason why you want it to be as automated as possible; you can’t expect your employees to remember this all of the time if they’re sending manually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you were to trigger the automation from within the project management system, you’ll probably have to go through Zapier again and trigger the feedback email with the properly tagged link in a mail system like MailChimp possibly even combining that with CRM information pulled into MailChimp by Zapier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exact details of how to do it depend on the systems that you use, but hopefully by now you have some idea of how these can all work together .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Closing the (Optional) Loop&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the basic setup done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there’s one more thing that you might want to do and that is send your NPS survey results back to CRM so that you can run segmented NPS reports against things like different services or business divisions and see which teams are doing best and which areas of the business you need to focus on improving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing you will need to do is create fields to hold this data in your CRM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are going to need fields for the NPS Score (number field), NPS Comments (text field), and NPS Date (date field).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The date is really important because that is what will let you run reports on the score over the last quarter or year. If you were to use something like project completion date, you might run in to situations where you do several projects with a client who, for example, only fills out your first NPS survey but then contributes to your recent score.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With those three fields set up, fire up Zapier again and create a new Zap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Link &lt;strong&gt;Typeform&lt;/strong&gt; with a &lt;strong&gt;New Entry&lt;/strong&gt; trigger to your CRM with an &lt;strong&gt;Update Contact&lt;/strong&gt; action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Typeform Trigger with CRM Action in Zapier" src="../assets/images/2016/typeform-trigger-crm-action-1e349ebf.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go through the various connection steps (which will depend partly on your CRM) and then match the email from Typeform to your CRM email field to match your data to the right record.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Match Typeform and CRM Email Fields" src="../assets/images/2016/match-typeform-crm-email-e1fa5a6e.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then connect your NPS data to the new fields in CRM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I ran in to a bug at this step where Zapier couldn’t detect the NPS fields that we’d created and initialized with the first test submission. I fixed the problem by submitting my Typeform a second time and redoing this integration.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Connect Typeform and CRM Fields" src="../assets/images/2016/connect-typeform-crm-b07a528a.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Test your integration, name it and you are done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was a long post, but it’s worth it. Now you are automatically asking your happiest customers for online reviews which will help you get more business while getting feedback that will help you analyze and improve your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well done.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Asking for Google Reviews</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/asking-google-reviews"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/asking-google-reviews</id>
    <published>2015-11-30T16:00:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2016-02-22T14:06:34-08:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Getting reviews in Google helps improve your footprint in Google search results with review content and helps you get shown on Google Maps results. Reviews may even help improve your ranking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of good reasons to get reviews on Google proper. Google even encourages you to ask your customers for reviews, so you’re not going to run afoul of their terms of service running a Google review campaign. Just remember that offering payment or discounts in exchange for a review will likely require some form of disclosure to not run afoul of truth in advertising laws.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is that Google has made it difficult to review your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some ways of currently linking directly to review forms, but these links often change and become invalid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way of getting reviews is directly through the search results. This lets you give instructions that aren’t going to change greatly as long as Google continues to support reviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Reviews on Google Search Results&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get a review on Google Search Results, you’ll need to ask the customer to search for your site on Google or you can do the search yourself and give them a link to the search results page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, you’ll need to instruct the customer to click on the Write a Review link in the business information box (also known as the Knowledge Panel results) on the right side of the search results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Branded Google Search on Desktop" src="../assets/images/2015/insul-twin-desktop-67e6f6ec.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s a couple of extra steps, but it is fairly straightforward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On mobile, it is a little more complicated with the review system hidden behind a white on blue disclosure caret signalling that more information is available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Branded Google Search on Mobile" src="../assets/images/2015/insul-twin-mobile-1-18637125.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then they’ll need to scroll down until they start seeing stars. No, really, check the screenshot below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Branded Google Search on Mobile Review Section" src="../assets/images/2015/insul-twin-mobile-2-28e7b5a8.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, that’s about the best that we can do for reviews right now. There are other solutions, but they break if you’re not signed in and Google’s been very flaky about supporting review URLs.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>When to Use HTML and Plain Text Emails</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://blog.url.com/blog/html-plain-text-email"/>
    <id>http://blog.url.com/blog/html-plain-text-email</id>
    <published>2015-11-14T16:00:00-08:00</published>
    <updated>2016-03-01T11:38:26-08:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;HTML emails are prettier than plain text. They require more expertise to produce than is seen in the average email user. As a result, business owners and managers are attracted to highly-designed HTML emails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But this barrier to entry often means that HTML emails are the wrong choice for communicating with customers and leads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;When HTML is the Wrong Answer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main problem with highly-designed emails is that they don’t look like the kind of email you get from friends and colleagues. They immediately put their recipients on guard for marketing messages and the quality of design and messaging needs to overcome this disadvantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This makes HTML a bad choice for drip emails. Typically drip emails are automated emails chains that take on the tone of a conversation between the prospect and someone at the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The email then needs to seem like it is coming from the company representative and any design beyond proper punctuation is going to undermine the purpose of the email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;When HTML is the Right Answer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A highly-designed HTML newsletter is a different situation. Even if your language is friendly and personal, the recipients expect that they are receiving a message from a company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s another important consideration with respect to design and branding when planning an HTML email—and that’s content. In particular, how the content of the email reflects on the brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A strong and consistent visual brand brand combined with excellent content trains recipients to respond favorably to the brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember that people receiving your emails are going to be most strongly imprinted with your brand as they are exposed to it repeatedly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conversely, if you send emails with strongly branded visuals but poor content then you are going to train these same people to react unfavorably. Until they unsubscribe, but people stay subscribed to emails they don’t care for much too long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Designing emails is a lot of work. Trust me, if you don’t know how much work they are, then you don’t want to find out. HTML emails are a nightmare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it is still relatively inexpensive for a manager or owner to spend on some nice email templates compared with the consistent on-going effort required to produce excellent content for those emails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until you’re in a position where you can consistently produce excellent content, spending on emails with a strong brand design is going to hurt your brand more than it will help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your brand is more than just design and logos. The content plays a part too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve seen too many strong brands send bad emails to stay silent on the subject.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
